<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
<!--Spell Attack rolls assume PROF added to roll, not applicable for Ranged while engaged in Melee range-->
<!--replaced ":" as intro to list with ".", and as in-line text with " - "-->
  <spell>
    <name>Spirit Shroud</name>
    <level>3</level>
    <school>N</school>
    <time>1 bonus action</time>
    <range>Self</range>
    <components>V, S</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
    <classes>Cleric, Paladin, Warlock, Wizard</classes>
    <text>You call forth spirits of the dead, which flit around you for the spell's duration. The spirits are intangible and invulnerable.</text>
    <text>Until the spell ends, any attack you make deals 1d8 extra damage when you hit a creature within 10 feet of you. This damage is radiant, necrotic, or cold (your choice when you cast the spell). Any creature that takes this damage can't regain hit points until the start of your next turn.</text>
    <text>In addition, any creature of your choice that you can see that starts its turn within 10 feet of you has its speed reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</text>
    <text/>
    <text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels above 3rd.</text>
    <text>Source: TCOE pg. 108</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
    <name>Summon Celestial</name>
    <level>5</level>
    <school>C</school>
    <time>1 action</time>
    <range>90 feet</range>
    <components>V, S, M (a gold reliquary worth at least 500 gp)</components>
    <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
    <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
    <text>You call forth a celestial spirit. It manifests in an angelic form in an unoccupied space that you can see within range. This corporeal form uses the Celeslial Spirit stat block. When you cast the spell, choose Avenger or Defender. Your choice determines the creature's attack in its stat block. The creature disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
    <text>The creature is an ally to you and your companions. In combat, the creature shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don't issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its move to avoid danger.</text>
    <text/>
    <text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, use the higher level wherever the spell's level appears in the stat block.</text>
    <text>Source: TCOE pg. 110</text>
  </spell>
</compendium>